CI is where everything begins.
It's the engine that tells you your code compiles,
your tests passed, your container image is secure,
and your build artifact is ready to deploy.
And if your CI pipeline breaks, your entire delivery process comes to a halt.
Let's just see how we can build this continuous
integration with the cloud build.
Let me create a folder.
Now, let's go inside that folder, and let's create one file.
I'm using an open editor now.
Inside this folder, let me create a file,
quickstart.sh, and let's have this Hello, world code inside that.
Let's create one more file that is a Dockerfile.
Now inside my Dockerfile,
I'm just writing this small code saying FROM Alpine, COPY
quickstart.sh, and CMD/quickstart.sh.
Now go back to the terminal window, and let me say here chmod and
give the execute permission on quickstart.sh.
Now type in the command saying gcloud artifacts
repositories create quickstart‑docker‑repo1,
and you give the location and format as docker.
Let's enter.
It will take a while, and then it will create the repository.
Use the gcloud builds submit command to build the
Docker image using a Dockerfile.
You don't require a separate cloud‑built config file.
Let's get your cloud project ID by running the following command.
Now use the same project ID and write the command gcloud builds submit.
Give the region,
give tag which contains your project ID and entire repo information,
and say Enter.
Now you can see that it has started the build.
Now it's pushing the repository image,
and then you can see that it is successful.
So now what we can do is we can go to our UI and search for cloud build.
And there we should be able to see the build that we have generated just now.
You can see that we got this one build ready.
You can click on that build and you can see the build ID.
If you come down to our console, you can see the ID here, f53,
which exactly is the same you can see here at the top.
So this is the specific build which we have created.
If you want to go inside the build artifacts,
you can see the name of the image as well.
Later on, if you want to see the repository, you can see the repositories here.
And if you want to add the triggers, for example,
you want this build to get automatically generated whenever
some triggers happens up like trigger could be when somebody
pushes something inside the repository or maybe someone pushes
a new tag or a pull request,
and in that case, you automatically wanted to create the trigger,
you can just set that trigger here, and that will run the build for you.
You can make this build automated.